發言。
立法會主席。
Thank you, Mr. President.
2018，tabled in this council today.
在 my capacity as member of the advisory committee of corruption.
Let me now turn to prevention. Prevention is better than cure.
我 hereby brief members on the Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC) annual report.
have not encountered corruption personally in the in the past 12 months. It clearly indicated.
As reviewed in the ICAC annual survey 2018, 19.8.4% of the respondents.
to give members of this council and the general public early access to the report, the ICAC has uploaded the report to its website on ten July two thousand and nine.
石禮謙議員就香港特別行政區廉政公署二零一八年報及廉政公署諮詢委員會報告向本會發言，石禮謙議。
The 2018 ICAC annual report was originally scheduled for tabling in the Legislative Council meeting on the 10th of July 2019, which, however, was cancelled.
fighting corruption is a long-term and uphill battle. The ICAC continues to adopt a three-pronged strategy, combining law enforcement, prevention and education in the fight against corruption.
部門，和7%涉及公營機構，總共97起選舉相關的腐敗舉報被接獲，包括64起涉及2018立法會選舉的舉報。
firstly, law enforcement. The ICAC discharges the enforcement duties impartially, making corruption a high risk crime with strong deterrent effects. In two thousand and nine, the corruption situation in Hong Kong continues to be well under control.
indicated a very low level of corruption in Hong Kong. Last year, the ICAC have received two six hundred and sixty five non-election related corruption complaints, about sixty six percent which concerned the private sector, twenty seven percent related to government.
係。
The issue on education.
The ICAC also offer corruption prevention advice to private organisations.
The battle against corruption could not be won without transforming people's attitudes toward corruption.
corruption prevention trainings are also conducted for over eight thousand four hundred people in both public and private sectors.
800 organisations enriching over 1 million people through various joint projects and community engagement activities.
The ICAC continues to enhance systems and regulations to eliminate corruption loopholes and opportunities in both public and private sectors.
appoint requests on eight hundred and ninety five occasions and handle eight hundred and forty nine public enquiries via the corruption prevention advisory hotline.
虛擬現實和增強現實科技，來讓市民體驗各種腐敗案件的模擬，在遊戲模擬中。
In this connection, the ICAC reaches out to the community, endeavouring to sustain a zero tolerance of corruption amongst the public, and encourage them to embrace integrity and ethical principles.
包括的全面審視有關品質控制系統的大型建築材料及政府工程，的管理、體育設施及場館的管理，以及私營的Colombia。
在2018， in 2018， the ICAZ completed 69 prevention studies, 62 of which related to government departments and public bodies, and seven concerned private organisations. These studies cover a wide range of operation systems and functions.
In addition, the ICAC provided tailor-made corruption prevention input to governments' initiatives on 559 occasions to ensure corruption prevention safeguards are incorporated in the formulation and early implementation stages of policies and procedures.
In two thousand and eight, the ICAC continued its robust effort to entrench the culture of propriety in the society, including organising nine hundred and twenty integrity training seminars for over forty thousand civil servants and staff members of the public bodies.
和零容忍， of corruption.
and a high degree of transparency serve to enhance government integrity.
自由，The think tank applauded Hong Kong for having a high quality
2018， active and constructive dialogue on training collaboration.
have been maintained with anti-corruption agencies of over 30 jurisdictions.
legal framework that strongly supports the rule of law, that there is little tolerance of corruption.
most respondents said they would report corruption if they come across one， indicating high social trust in the work of the ICAC。
在ICAC年度survey，， general public demand demonstrated determination in upholding the core value of integrity.
with this, I hope members of the public will continue to render their wholehearted support to the ICAC as always. Thank you, Mr. President. 林建炎就廉政公署事宜。
In November 2008, the ICAC sent experienced trainers to Myanmar and Cambodia to conduct training programmes for officers of their anti-corruption agencies.
amid the advancement of globalisation and the increasing cross-border corruption, international cooperation and collaboration is of utmost importance in the war against corruption.
enriching forty four thousand staff members of various trades through anti-corruption training, hosting its first ever youth integrity fest to engage young people to apply their creativity to spread the core value of probity, garnering support from over eight.
rolling out a multi-language publicity package to convey don't bribe and report corruption messages to ethnic minorities, new arrival and the general public. The ICAC also develop interactive game modules using.
主席和 fellow members，  both local and international surveys indicated that the value of poverty is deeply entrenched in our society. The Heritage Foundation ranked Hong Kong the world's freest economy for 25 consecutive years in its 2019 Index of Economic
Apart from undertaking the anti-corruption mission locally, the ICAC also shoulders the obligations to help build up the capacity of anti-corruption agencies of other jurisdictions under the framework of the United Nations Convention against Corruption. At the end.
主席和各位議員，今年是45週年紀。香港已走過一段長途，在轉型上從一個受腐敗的城邦，變成一個國際大都會。我作為諮詢委員會成員，
理解、理解。理解。